Brennan Smallwood

Phone: 425.590.7598 | Email: smallwoodbrennan@gmail.com LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/brennan-smallwood-422155a1/ |

GitHub: https://github.com/BSmalls6

Portfolio: https://brennan-portfolio-2020.herokuapp.com/

Design, Develop, Write, Produce

Digital creative capable of researching, designing and developing software, content and more. Certifications in full-stack development and UX design, as well as a bachelors in digital communication. HTML, CSS, ECMA6, Node.JS, React and more. My strengths include creative problem solving, leadership and idea generation. Successfully developed a system for gathering/analyzing data to track key KPI's for individual designers and developers by combining the analysis tools of Jira with some personal creativity

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP

Libraries: React, JQuery, Fuse.js, Node.js, Express.js, Socket.io, Materialize.ui

Database: SQL, Mongo, MySQL, Robo3t

Technologies: JIRA, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Premiere, After Effects), Github, Git, Bash,

inVision, Postman

Projects

Favr - https://farvbarter.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/CeeJtheDay/barterApp

2020

Full-stack web app that allows user to barter goods and services without money

- Led a team of four in creating a full-stack web app that uses robust database and search engine technology to match users whose needs and offered services matched, and allowed them to communicate/coordinate the barter.
- Tools used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS, Fuse.js (search engine), React.js, Materialize UI, MongoDB

Lounge - https://github.com/BSmalls6/lounge_project
2019

Digital shared music experience that allowed users to create a collaborative, custom playlist and chat

- This app allows users to create "lounges" with their friends/other users that included a dynamic playlist that anyone could update, and a chat room
- Tools used: HTML5, CSS3, Materialize CSS, SQL, JavaScript, jQuery,Socket.io, and Deezer.api

Experience

Sesame Communications, Seattle | Web Producer Aug 2018 - Present

As a web producer at Sesame Communications, I oversee the creation of custom websites from design to launch, doing a little bit of everything in-between to help clients achieve the perfect new website. **Key Achievements:**

Designed new on-boarding system for new clients to more effectively set expectations

 Created a new PHP component that allowed clients greater editing power on previously inaccessible pages

MedBridge, Seattle | Multimedia Producer

Nov 2016 - July 2018

As a Producer at MedBridge, I produced educational multimedia content from filming to release. This included coordinating my team's schedule leveraging my technical skills to speed projects and creating custom content.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Data Analyst and KPI Creator I created KPI's for the production and development teams and created tools for pulling data from mostly qualitative work
- Content Creator I researched, wrote and produced a series of short, educational videos to supplement the content library

Microsoft, Redmond| Video Production Intern

May 2015 - August 2016

As an Intern at Microsoft, I assisted various teams with multimedia productions. Productions included live-streaming of Microsoft CEO speeches, product education videos and virtual reality capture.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Programmed over 50 virtual machines for in-store displays.
- Assisted in the development of virtual reality capture software and implementation

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development | Seattle, WA

University of Washington | 2019-2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in JavaScript, SQL and No-SQL Databases, HTML/CSS, React, Node.js, algorithms and data structures.

University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ | Digital Communication

Bachelors of Arts | 2012-2016

Major: Communication and Media Studies

Minor: Environmental Studies

General Assembly UX/UI Certification

Web Design Circuit Bootcamp | 2018

A 12 week bootcamp focused on UX/UI design and front-end development.